Chenkai Weng

+1-224-307-3331 | ckweng@u.northwestern.edu | ckweng.github.io

Research Interests

My research interest lies in cryptography, with a focus on secure multi-party computation and zero-knowledge proofs. I have participated in projects related to VOLE-based interactive zero-knowledge proofs, the concrete security of garbled circuits protocol, efficient correlated oblivious transfer and private data aggregations.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University

Evanston, IL

PhD in Computer Science; Advisor: Xiao Wang

Sept. 2019 - Present

Xidian University

Xi'an, China

BSc in Information Security

Sept. 2015 – June 2019

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - Present

- Scalable and Efficient interactive zero-knowledge protocols based on VOLE.
- Design of efficient VOLEs.
- Concrete security of the garbled circuit protocol.
- Design, implementation and evaluation of MPC/ZK applications.

Co-lecturer

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Jan. 2023 - Mar. 2023

• Advanced topics in cryptography: OT-extension, BGW, MPC-in-the-head, PSI.

Research Intern

Remote

Chainlink Lab

Oct. 2022 - May. 2023

• Design and development of decentralized oracle system.

AI Research Summer Associate

New York, NY

JPMorgan Chase

Jun. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Research on dishonest-majority maliciously-secure multi-party computation protocol.

Research Intern Microsoft Research Remote

May. 2021 – Jul. 2021

• Design and Develop secure multi-party computation and differential privacy applications for private aggregation.

Teaching Assistant

Evanston, IL

Northwestern University

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Introduction to Cryptography

Security Engineering Intern

Beijing, China

Alibaba Group

July 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Survey on secure multi-party computation techniques.
- Implementation of threshold encryption and digital signature schemes based on MPC.
- Implementation of private set intersection protocol and order-preserving encryption schemes.

Publications

1. SUPERPACK: Dishonest Majority MPC with Constant Online Communication

Daniel Escudero, Vipul Goyal, Antigoni Polychroniadou, Yifan Song, Chenkai Weng Annual International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptology and Information Security (Eurocrypt), 2023

2. AntMan: Interactive Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Sublinear Communication

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Zhaomin Yang, Xiang Xie, and Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2022

3. More Efficient Secure Matrix Multiplication for Unbalanced Recommender Systems

Zhicong Huang, Cheng Hong, Wen-jie Lu, Chenkai Weng, Hunter Qu IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (TDSC)

4. Constant-Overhead Zero-Knowledge for RAM Programs

Nicholas Franzese, Jonathan Katz, Steve Lu, Rafail Ostrovsky, Xiao Wang, Chenkai Weng ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021

5. Efficient Conversions for Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Applications to Machine Learning

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Xiang Xie, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang USENIX Security Symposium, 2021

6. Efficient and Affordable Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Circuits and Polynomials over Any Field

Kang Yang, Pratik Sarkar, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021

7. Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Boolean and Arithmetic Circuits

Chenkai Weng, Kang Yang, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland), 2021

8. Developing High Performance Secure Multi-Party Computation Protocols in Healthcare: A Case Study of Patient Risk Stratification

Xiao Dong, David Randolph, Chenkai Weng, Abel Kho, Jennie Rogers, Xiao Wang AMIA Informatics Summit, 2021

9. Ferret: Fast Extension for coRRElated oT with small communication

Kang Yang, Chenkai Weng, Xiao Lan, Jiang Zhang, Xiao Wang ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2020

10. Better Concrete Security for Half-Gates Garbling (in the Multi-Instance Setting)

Chun Guo, Jonathan Katz, Xiao Wang, Chenkai Weng, Yu Yu International Cryptology Conference (CRYPTO), 2020

Talks

- 1. Nov. 2022 "AntMan: Interactive Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Sublinear Communication", at ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2022.
- 2. Sept. 2022 "Efficient Interactive Zero Knowledge Proof Based on VOLE", at Yale University CS talk.
- 3. Nov. 2021 "QuickSilver: Efficient and Affordable Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Circuits and Polynomials over Any Field", ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2021.
- 4. Aug. 2021 "Efficient Conversions for Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Applications to Machine Learning", USENIX Security Symposium, 2021.
- 5. May. 2021 "Wolverine: Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Boolean and Arithmetic Circuits", IEEE Security & privacy (Oakland), 2021.
- 6. Mar. 2021 "Fast, Scalable, and Communication-Efficient Zero-Knowledge Proofs", Security and privacy seminar at Duke University.

- 7. Nov. 2020 "Ferret: Fast Extension for coRRElated oT with small communication", ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2020.
- 8. Aug. 2020 "Better Concrete Security for Half-Gates Garbling (in the Multi-Instance Setting)", International Cryptology Conference (CRYPTO), 2020.

SERVICE

Conference: external reviewer for CRYPTO 21 22 23, ITC 22, Asiacrypt 22, IEEE S&P 23, PKC 23.

Journal: TDSC, TIFS, TOPS.

AWARDS

- 1. Runner-up for Best Paper Awards, CCS 2021.
- 2. PhD Student Research Award, Computer Science Department, Northwestern University, 2020-2021.

Software

EMP library

- 1. [EMP-TOOL] Float-point arithmetic based on Boolean circuits. Cryptographic building blocks.
- 2. [EMP-OT] Correlated-OT based on VOLE (The Ferret protocol).
- 3. [EMP-ZK] Interactive zero-knowledge proof protocols. For the circuit model, it supports boolean and arithmetic circuits, and their conversions. It also supports proving degree-2 polynomial satisfiabilies.